<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<articlearchive>
    <articles>
        <article>
            <id>1</id>
            <title>House Armed Services Chair Mike Rogers (R-Ala.) said he'll be in Paris — not reviewing the troops and materiel his panel oversees.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/10/trump-parade-congress-republicans-00398774</link>
            <description>POLITICO surveyed 50 Hill Republicans. Only seven said they'd stick around Saturday for the show.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T19:17:51</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>3</id>
                <name>Lisa</name>
                <surname>Kashinsky</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\30e7018c-9e8e-44c0-ad60-6db872f02723.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump is celebrating the Army’s 250th anniversary — and his own 79th birthday — with a massive, multimillion-dollar military parade Saturday in Washington.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But one group of otherwise devoted Trump allies largely won’t be there to celebrate: congressional Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Among the 50 GOP lawmakers surveyed by POLITICO, only seven said they planned to stay in Washington this weekend for the festivities. Those begging off include members of the Republican leadership in both chambers.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The chairs of the House and Senate Armed Services committees, the top congressional officials overseeing the military, are skipping Trump’s pageantry, which includes a flyover of vintage and contemporary warplanes. Instead, they’ll attend a different air show — the annual defense industry confab in Paris.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Among those attending will be some of Trump’s most devoted House supporters, such as Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene of Georgia. “Yes, of course,” she said Tuesday. “I’m going to be there for the 250th anniversary of the Army.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;MAGA stalwarts Byron Donalds of Florida, Elise Stefanik of New York and Cory Mills of Florida also said they would attend, along with Reps. Rich McCormick of Georgia, John McGuire of Virginia and Lisa McClain of Michigan.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But many more said they would beg off — choosing, as most members do, to stay away from Washington for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Majority Leader John Thune and Majority Whip John Barrasso are skipping, as is House Majority Leader Steve Scalise. Sen. Tommy Tuberville said he’ll be back in Alabama campaigning for governor. Oklahoma Sen. Markwayne Mullin said it’s his anniversary, and “I choose to be married.” Rep. Tim Burchett of Tennessee said the event conflicts with his daughter’s 18th birthday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;West Virginia Sen. Jim Justice said he’s a no but added that doesn’t “mean that I’m against it.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great celebrating President Trump’s birthday, and I think it’s great celebrating the military,” Justice told reporters Tuesday. “We haven’t done that in a long time.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Among those skipping are several military veterans and members of the two Armed Services panels. South Carolina Sen. Lindsey Graham, a former Air Force reservist, said Tuesday he’s not planning to attend, though he left open the possibility. Other senators who have served in the military and are planning to sit out the celebration include Sens. Todd Young of Indiana, Rick Scott of Florida and Tim Sheehy of Montana.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Foreign Affairs Committee Chair Brian Mast of Florida, another veteran, said Tuesday he’s unsure whether he’ll attend.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Other prominent House Republicans are also skipping. House Freedom Caucus Chair Andy Harris said he won’t attend, though his home is less than a two-hour drive from D.C. House Appropriations Chair Tom Cole said he’s heading home.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s celebrating the birthday of the Army and I think it’s a good thing to do,” Cole said. “I just didn’t get to go home last week and I’d like to get to go this week.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked if he was attending, Senate Armed Services Chair Roger Wicker of Mississippi said, “I’ll be at the air show” — an apparent reference to next week’s Paris Air Show, where defense contractors peddle their latest wares. House Armed Services Chair Mike Rogers of Alabama confirmed that’s where he’ll be.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaker Mike Johnson’s office did not respond to a request for comment on his plans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The White House is shrugging off the absences. An official granted anonymity to describe plans for the event said senior military leaders and at least 15 Cabinet members, including Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth and Veterans Affairs Secretary Doug Collins, are expected to attend.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“President Trump looks forward to a historic crowd at the Army Birthday Parade, where he will be joined by top military leaders, administration officials, congressional representatives, and most importantly, thousands of patriotic Americans to celebrate 250 years of honor, courage, and sacrifice by our United States military,” White House spokesperson Anna Kelly said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Many Hill Republicans have shrugged off the parade’s hefty price tag. But a &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/05/congress/gop-senators-question-cost-of-armys-parade-spectacle-00390271" target="_blank"&gt;few have raised concerns&lt;/a&gt;. Army Secretary Dan Driscoll said in an Army budget hearing last week that the costs could range from $25 million to $40 million. He said he could not provide an exact estimate because the Army could not predict how much damage its tanks would do to the District’s streets, potentially necessitating costly repairs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to take anything away from celebrating the anniversary of our armed forces if it helps with recruiting and patriotism,” Rep. Dan Newhouse of Washington said in a brief interview. “But it depends on what that number is. If it’s $100 million, it causes one to pause.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Military leaders have defended the parade as a vital recruiting tool. But Democrats have railed against the administration for prioritizing pageantry over service members and their families. The parade, set to run along the north side of the National Mall, begins near the Pentagon — in the Virginia district represented by Democratic Rep. Don Beyer, who sees the event as a waste of money.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Like his deployment of the military in L.A., it’s a shocking waste of money at a time they are closing Social Security offices ‘to save money,’” Beyer said in a statement. “They’re shutting down our regional transportation including the airport for this, and people I hear from in the military don’t even want it, the whole thing is just to boost Trump’s fragile ego.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump warned Tuesday that protesters who show up to the Saturday parade will be met with “very big force.” Demonstrations to counter the parade are &lt;a href="https://www.nokings.org/district" target="_blank"&gt;planned for other cities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Beyer said Trump’s threat only added to “the trappings of authoritarianism” the parade already carried.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Roughly 6,600 troops are expected in Washington. The Army plans to roll 25 M1 Abrams main battle tanks and 150 vehicles down Constitution Avenue. A World War II-vintage B-25 bomber and P-1 fighter will join the parade, along with Vietnam-era Huey helicopters. Soldiers marching in the parade will wear uniforms from every conflict the U.S. has fought, from the Revolutionary War to the present day.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jordain Carney, Ben Jacobs and Meredith Lee Hill contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;CORRECTION: An earlier version of this story misstated how many of the 50 surveyed members said they would attend the parade. It is seven.</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>2</id>
            <title>Senate GOP finalizing scaled-down food stamp cuts after backlash</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/senate-republicans-food-aid-cost-share-plan-reconciliation-00398049</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T15:54:58</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>3</id>
            <title>Senior House Republican sends warning to White House on funding clawbacks</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/senior-house-republican-warns-against-pocket-rescissions-00397937</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T15:22:07</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;At least one senior congressional appropriator isn’t interested in White House budget chief Russ Vought’s enthusiasm for so-called “pocket rescissions,” which would allow the Trump administration to make permanent cuts to federal spending without congressional approval.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I think it's a bad idea,” Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51623" data-person-id="51623"&gt;Mike Simpson&lt;/a&gt; (R-Idaho), chair of the Interior-Environment subcommittee, told reporters Tuesday. “It undermines Congress's authority.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A pocket rescission is a standard rescission request from the White House to claw back money already approved by Congress, but one that is made with fewer than forty-five days left in the fiscal year. The administration then withholds the funding through Sept. 30, in an attempt to permanently cancel it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Government Accountability Office has concluded that using the maneuver in that way is not true to the law. Yet Vought has repeatedly brought up the concept in television appearances and private meetings on Capitol Hill, touting the pocket rescission as a tool at the administration’s disposal if Congress can’t or won’t green-light the executive branch’s cancellation of funding that both chambers already approved.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Simpson said the president needs to evaluate bills that come to his desk as a whole, just like lawmakers have to routinely swallow certain provisions in large pieces of legislation they wouldn’t support as standalone propositions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“What I've been saying is, if the president doesn't like a bill, he has to look at it just like we do every appropriation bill — I can find something I don't like in there. He has to look at it and say, ‘is it good, is it bad’ — in total — and then you have to live with the parts that you might not like,” said Simpson. “That’s the way it’s supposed to work.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Congressional Republicans are currently weighing the administration’s first rescissions request of $9.4 billion spending cuts across foreign aid programs and public media. It’s not guaranteed that the package will have the votes for passage, however, and the Trump administration is anticipating that future packages may not be able to win broad support, either.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“If there is not a political will, particularly in the Senate, and then put ourselves in a position where we have lost other executive tools that exist, namely pocket rescissions, to be able to make these cuts permanent without having to get an affirmative vote from the House and the Senate,” Vought told reporters on a recent call.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Majority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/59655" data-person-id="59655"&gt;Steve Scalise&lt;/a&gt; told reporters Tuesday he welcomes more rescissions packages, “because clearly, there's a lot more we want to cut, and I'm sure there's a lot more they want to cut.” But he didn’t comment directly on the pocket rescission strategy Vought has been touting.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We're going to have a conversation with [the White House] to talk about what the long-term goal is going to be,” said Scalise.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jennifer Scholtes contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>4</id>
            <title>Eleanor Holmes Norton is 'in conversations' about reelection amid age questions</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/eleanor-holmes-norton-reelection-00397248</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T14:30:43</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Eleanor Holmes Norton, D.C.'s nonvoting House delegate, is entertaining the possibility of retiring after 18 terms in office, a spokesperson said Tuesday, hours after Norton herself told reporters she intended to run again.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The spokesperson, Sharon Eliza Nichols, said Norton "wants to wants to run again but she’s in conversations with her family, friends, and closest advisors to decide what’s best."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Earlier Tuesday, Norton told reporters she intends to seek reelection amid mounting questions about her ability to serve in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, sure,” she said when asked about seeking reelection. Asked how she would respond to critics who have questioned her abilities at age 87, replied, “I'm going to run. I don't know why anybody would even ask me.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Multiple &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonian.com/2025/04/17/does-eleanor-holmes-norton-still-have-what-it-takes-to-fight-for-dc/" target="_blank"&gt;recent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/06/06/eleanor-holmes-norton-age/" target="_blank"&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2025/05/eleanor-holmes-norton-dcs-sole-congressional-rep-is-too-old-to-drive-can-she-defend-the-city-from-a-hostile-gop/" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; have surfaced concerns about about Norton, who turns 88 this week and has served as D.C’s delegate since 1991. She has become a &lt;a href="https://x.com/HowardMortman/status/1931676243520327730" target="_blank"&gt;less visible presence&lt;/a&gt; on the House floor, and her halting engagement has concerned some local officials and activists. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One prominent former aide and longtime confidant, Democratic strategist Donna Brazile, told the Washington Post last week, "It’s time to turn things over."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The new scrutiny comes as D.C. faces multiple threats from President Donald Trump and the GOP-controlled Congress, which teed up bills this week focusing on policies in the heavily Democratic city. The District faced &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/05/05/congress/speaker-says-house-will-vote-as-quickly-as-possible-on-district-of-columbia-budget-fix-00330426" target="_blank"&gt;major funding shortfall&lt;/a&gt; after a March stopgap government funding bill failed to allow the city to spend its updated local budget, prompting a scramble to fill a budget hole city officials estimated at $1 billion. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Senate approved legislation to fix the shortfall, but the House hasn’t taken it up yet. Asked Tuesday whether it was important for Speaker Mike Johnson to bring that legislation up for a House vote, Norton replied, “No.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Nichols said Norton misheard the question and believed reporters were asking about the D.C.-related bills on the House floor this week. Nichols said Norton meant to say those bills aren’t of national importance and were contrary to D.C. residents’ own decisions about their government and believed they shouldn’t have been introduced or brought to the House floor.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>5</id>
            <title>Former Biden aides agree to testify on his mental acuity to House Oversight</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/biden-aides-investigation-house-oversight-tanden-00397036</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T13:25:27</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Four senior Biden White House aides agreed to testify to the House Oversight Committee as part of its probe into former President Joe Biden’s ailing health while in office, according to a committee aide.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Their testimony schedule: &lt;br&gt;— Neera Tanden, former director of the Domestic Policy Council, on June 24&lt;br&gt;— Anthony Bernal, former senior adviser to the First Lady, on June 26&lt;br&gt;— Ashley Williams, former deputy director of Oval Office operations, on July 11&lt;br&gt;— Annie Tomasini, former deputy chief of staff, on July 18&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Chair James Comer had requested the aides’ cooperation with his investigation in May, amid renewed scrutiny in Washington of the former president’s mental acuity. Last week, the Kentucky Republican sent a subpoena to Biden’s physician Kevin O’Connor, calling him to appear on June 27 after O’Connor rejected Comer’s invitation to testify.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even after Biden largely retreated from public view, congressional Republicans have focused extensively on concerns around the octogenarian former president’s health. The Senate will hold a hearing on the matter next week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Comer has also requested testimony from former senior adviser to the president Michael Donilon; former senior adviser to the president Anita Dunn; former deputy chief of staff Bruce Reed; and former counselor to the president Steve Ricchetti.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In response to a similar White House probe into whether aides contributed to a cover-up of Biden’s decline, Biden has maintained that he drove his own decisions during his presidency. There is no evidence aides acted on his behalf in response to his ailing health.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>6</id>
            <title>Trump's California troop deployment is impeachable, CBC chair says</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/yvette-clarke-cbc-impeachment-trump-troops-00396688</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T11:56:31</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The chair of the Congressional Black Caucus said President Donald Trump should be impeached over the deployment of the National Guard in Los Angeles in response to recent street clashes over immigration enforcement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I definitely believe it is. But we'll cross that bridge when we get to it,” Rep. Yvette Clarke of New York said Tuesday when asked at a news conference if she considered Trump's decision to send in the troops over the objections of state and local officials an impeachable offense.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Other Democrats didn’t go as far when asked about impeachment Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We'll cross that bridge when we get there,” Rep. Adriano Espaillat (D-N.Y.), chair of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus, said in an interview. “I have to study all the facts. This is not over yet, but it certainly hasn't started out in a good way.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats have railed against the use of the National Guard to respond to the protests, calling it a threat to democracy. California plans to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/09/california-national-guard-lawsuit-gavin-newsom-00394609" target="_blank"&gt;sue over the use&lt;/a&gt; of the Guard, arguing Trump overstepped by deploying the troops without the sign-off of California Gov. Gavin Newsom, a Democrat.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The chaos is the bait and the switch is a constitutional crisis and power grab,” Rep. Jimmy Gomez (D-Calif.) told reporters at a separate news conference from Clarke's held earlier Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democratic leaders have generally tamped down any pushes to impeach Trump. An earlier effort by Rep. Shri Thanedar (D-Mich.) &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/05/14/congress/thanedar-pulls-impeachment-vote-00350361" target="_blank"&gt;fizzled out&lt;/a&gt; amid a fierce backlash in the party, and House Democratic Caucus Chair Pete Aguilar of California said "House Democrats aren't focused on impeachment today" when he addressed reporters after Clarke spoke Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"We are focused on holding the president and House Republicans accountable for the policies that attack the basic needs, like health care and food assistance," he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rank-and-file members such as Rep. Emily Randall (D-Wash.) are skeptical of the odds of success for impeachment with the House and Senate held by the GOP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“An impeachable offense and what we can actually get across the finish line are two different things, and we saw Donald Trump impeached twice and re-elected,” she said. “So do I think this is unconstitutional and un-American? Yes. Do I think the American people oppose it? Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>7</id>
            <title>White House tweaks AIDS funding rollback to assuage skeptical Republicans</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/pepfar-cuts-rescissions-aids-funding-00396385</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T08:48:57</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The White House is trying to assure House Republicans wary of plans to slash global AIDS funding that the administration will spare some prevention programs that would have been on the chopping block.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The promises come as GOP leaders race to shore up votes for a &lt;a href="https://legislation.politicopro.com/bill/US_119_HR_4" target="_blank"&gt;$9.4 billion spending cuts package&lt;/a&gt; ahead of a &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/white-house-request-for-funding-clawbacks-up-in-the-house-next-week-00391795" target="_blank"&gt;scheduled Thursday vote&lt;/a&gt;. The planned cuts to the President's Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief, a signature effort of former President George W. Bush that is credited with saving millions of lives, have been especially problematic for many Hill Republicans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In recent days, White House officials have conveyed to GOP leaders that they will not only maintain life-saving treatments under PEPFAR but will also — in response to concerns from more than a dozen House Republicans — preserve some prevention programs as well, according to three people granted anonymity to discuss the private assurances.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaker &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/242539" data-person-id="242539"&gt;Mike Johnson’s&lt;/a&gt; whip team spent Monday evening on the House floor counting votes on the overall "rescissions" package, which targets public broadcasting and broader foreign aid efforts, in addition to the hundreds of millions of dollars in overseas AIDS funding. The whip team conveyed the altered plans in conversations and text messages with lawmakers. Some Republican lawmakers have pressed the White House directly about Trump’s request to nix funding for fighting AIDS around the globe.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;White House budget director Russ Vought told appropriators last week that the Trump administration wants to take “an analytical look” at “the prevention itself” and instead fund “life-saving treatment” for people with AIDS. But Vought said the White House is still planning to scale down PEPFAR and other programs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It is something that our budget will be very trim on,” Vought said of funding AIDS prevention work, “because we believe that many of these nonprofits are not geared towards the viewpoints of the administration. And we're $37 trillion in debt. So at some point, the continent of Africa needs to absorb more of the burden of providing this health care.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers are also raising concerns about deep cuts across public media — targeting PBS and NPR, as well as their local affiliates.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Nevada Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/177013" data-person-id="177013"&gt;Mark Amodei&lt;/a&gt;, a top GOP appropriator, said in a brief interview Tuesday morning that he spoke with Majority Whip &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/227580" data-person-id="227580"&gt;Tom Emmer&lt;/a&gt; on the House floor Monday evening about trying to spare local PBS affiliates from deep funding cuts. Amodei said he is pressing for more information about how local affiliates get funding from the larger public media networks and if there is a way lawmakers can cut off the networks without harming the affiliates.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jennifer Scholtes contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>8</id>
            <title>Capitol agenda: GOP eyes cuts to Trump’s tax promises</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/10/congress/trump-taxes-tips-overtime-megabill-republicans-00396021</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-10T07:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Senate Finance Republicans are increasingly looking to dial back key items on President Donald Trump’s tax policy wish list. And it’s pitting them against the architect of the House-passed tax legislation, Ways and Means Chair Jason Smith — and potentially even the White House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The rub is this: The House version of the megabill would restore tax incentives for research and development, business equipment and debt interest through 2029, which Trump has indicated he supports. But Senate Republicans are dead-set on making them permanent, a proposition that would likely add hundreds of billions in more red ink to the legislation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To offset that cost, GOP senators are looking to water down other tax provisions they believe aren’t as “pro-growth.” Those policies include “no taxes on tips,” “no taxes on overtime” and tax relief for seniors — all proposals Trump touted on the campaign trail and collectively boast a price tag of roughly $230 billion, according to the Joint Committee on Taxation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Smith is warning senators to tread carefully in challenging Trump’s desires.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I think that the United States Senate will not want to scale down the president’s priorities. No tax on tips, no tax on overtime are two of his top priorities,” the Missouri Republican told reporters Monday. “Are there some tweaks that they can do to it that I would recommend? Yes, and I have recommended.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But some Senate Republicans who sit on the Finance panel have made clear they have their own ideas. When POLITICO asked Sen. Ron Johnson (R-Wis.) whether he believes “no tax on tips” or “no tax on overtime” are pro-growth, he gave a terse “nope.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“They’re making a case to increase the labor supply,” the Wisconsin Republican told POLITICO. “I would just extend the current tax law.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Thom Tillis (R-N.C.) has likewise been pushing to make changes to both policies, telling POLITICO on Monday that “no tax on overtime” should be rewritten to ensure it applies only to people working over 40 hours a week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;White House spokesperson Abigail Jackson said "No Tax on Overtime and No Tax on Tips are presidential priorities that 80 million Americans voted for in November."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"They will remain in this historic piece of legislation in order to deliver the largest tax cut in history," she added.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, House Republicans are hoping &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/house-technical-corrections-gop-megabill-00394907" target="_blank"&gt;to tweak some language&lt;/a&gt; in their bill they believe the Senate parliamentarian will identify as non-compliant with the budget reconciliation process. They’ll do so by using a procedural maneuver within the Rules Committee that won’t require the chamber to take a standalone vote on a revised measure, five people told POLITICO.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Republican leaders expect a report on the potential Senate problems Tuesday morning, though Majority Leader Steve Scalise (La.) acknowledged they may not have the full list before the Rules hearing scheduled for later Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I don't think there will be any big surprises,” Speaker Mike Johnson added Monday, “but that's part of the process.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What else we’re watching:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— Rescissions heads to Rules: &lt;/b&gt;The House Rules Committee is scheduled to vote on the White House’s rescissions package at 2 p.m. Tuesday, paving the way for a floor vote by Thursday. Johnson and Scalise are confident they can appease members’ concerns about clawing back money Congress has already green-lighted and slashing funding for the PEPFAR program and public media.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— Crypto vote imminent:&lt;/b&gt; Senate Majority Leader John Thune wants to pass landmark cryptocurrency legislation this week that would create new rules for dollar-pegged digital tokens. He &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/johnson-trumps-megabill-is-still-on-track-00394985" target="_blank"&gt;teed up the stablecoin bill for another procedural vote&lt;/a&gt; as soon as Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— Trump admins on the Hill: &lt;/b&gt;A slew of Trump administration officials will testify before various House and Senate committees Tuesday on the president’s fiscal 2026 budget requests for their agencies. That includes Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth, Joint Chiefs of Staff Chair Gen. Dan Caine, NIH Director Jay Bhattacharya, CIA Director John Ratcliffe and Energy Secretary Chris Wright.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jordain Carney, Jasper Goodman, Meredith Lee Hill and Jennifer Scholtes contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>9</id>
            <title>Mark Green says he'll retire from House after megabill vote</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/mark-green-to-retire-after-megabill-vote-00395343</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T17:21:10</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Rep. Mark Green said Monday he plans to resign from Congress after four terms to accept a private-sector job offer. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Tennessee Republican and Homeland Security Committee said his retirement would begin after the House votes again on the GOP's domestic-policy megabill now under consideration in the Senate. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I am grateful to Speaker Johnson and House Leadership for placing their trust in me to chair the Committee on Homeland Security, lead the effort to impeach former Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas, and to pass H.R. 2, the Secure the Border Act, the strongest border security legislation in history to ever pass the House,” Green &lt;a href="https://markgreen.house.gov/press-releases?id=C02CE940-281B-4FEE-85F7-A6E7134F4FAF" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “However, my time in Congress has come to an end.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Green announced last year he would retire but then reentered the race. Shortly before the election, his wife went public with allegations of an extramarital affair, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/13/mark-green-affair-accusation-legal-threats-00179148" target="_blank"&gt;which POLITICO corroborated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Green did not disclose the identity of his future employer. Under House rules, members are required to disclose negotiations with a future private employer to the Ethics Committee, and are required to recuse themselves from matters where their future employment would pose a conflict of interest. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for the Ethics Committee declined to comment on whether Green disclosed any job talks in advance.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The retirement could leave Johnson with a vacancy for several months. Under Tennessee law, GOP Gov. Bill Lee has to call a special election within 10 days after the vacancy is official, with the general election to be held between 100 and 107 days after that. The seat is considered safely Republican, with Donald Trump having won the district by 22 points last year. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>10</id>
            <title>House to make fixes to GOP megabill to avoid 'fatal' ruling with Senate parliamentarian</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/house-technical-corrections-gop-megabill-00394907</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T16:34:33</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Republicans will try to fix issues with their megabill in the Rules Committee this week based on provisions the Senate parliamentarian has identified as non-compliant with the chamber’s rules, according to five people with direct knowledge of the plans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republicans need to send their massive tax and spending package to the Senate to make its own changes. But without making certain revisions to the House-passed bill first, it could run afoul of the chamber's parliamentarian. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the words of one senior House GOP aide, granted anonymity to speak candidly, certain House-approved provisions could prove "fatal" to the bill's ability to comply with the rules surrounding the filibuster-skirting budget reconciliation process, which Republicans are relying upon to pass their domestic policy measure without Democratic votes.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House GOP leaders are currently working through the bill text and will either strike small pieces of the legislation or drop certain sections altogether. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One provision the parliamentarian has raised concerns about is a clearinghouse to crack down on duplicative food aid, Medicaid and other safety net benefits, according to two other people aware of the emerging plan. This issue is currently in limbo between two panel jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Among the many rules Senate Republicans must adhere to in a reconciliation bill is that it can’t include a policy that falls outside the jurisdiction of one of the committees empowered through the budget resolution Republicans approved in April to set parameters for the larger package. It also can’t include a policy that would affect federal spending, when the committee in question was instructed to change revenue.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers will work within the House Rules Committee to make these tweaks, according to the people, inserting the new language into an unrelated rule which the panel will adopt Tuesday to govern floor consideration for other legislation. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;That tactic would negate the need to have House Republicans vote on the party-line tax and spending package as a standalone measure, when passing the bill the first time around through a razor-thin GOP majority was a painful enough episode for leadership.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The GOP plan to make technical corrections to the megabill inside the Rules Committee was first reported by Punchbowl News.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>11</id>
            <title>Democratic senator seeks guardrails as Trump deploys troops to LA</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/blumenthal-trump-troop-deployments-insurrection-act-00395102</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T16:28:30</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s decision to deploy troops to Los Angeles in response to protests is driving a new push in Congress to rein in presidential power.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/151824" data-person-id="151824"&gt;Richard Blumenthal&lt;/a&gt; (D-Conn.) told POLITICO he is drafting new legislation to sharply limit a president’s ability to deploy troops on American soil — a move he says is urgently needed after the White House sent National Guard soldiers and Marines to the country’s second-largest city after raucous but relatively small demonstrations against immigration arrests.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The mainstream of America really believes deeply that our military should be used to defend our national interests and security, not to silence protest at home,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Blumenthal has &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/01/24/trump-insurrection-act-deploy-military-00137598" target="_blank"&gt;long sought to overhaul&lt;/a&gt; the Insurrection Act and related presidential powers with the goal of preventing a president from federalizing the National Guard or using active-duty forces domestically without speedy congressional oversight.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Under Blumenthal’s proposal, a president could deploy troops domestically for a strictly limited period, possibly 10 or 20 days, he said — after which congressional approval would be required. The restrictions would apply to active-duty and Guard units under federal command. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We’re sort of beginning to work on another version of it, which we hope to introduce,” Blumenthal said Monday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Trump has not invoked the Insurrection Act, but instead used a separate legal authority to deploy 2,000 National Guard troops to protect federal property and personnel amid protests in L.A. Critics, including Blumenthal, argue the move amounts to a “backdoor” attempt to deploy the military in ways that could violate constitutional rights.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Blumenthal’s office is reaching out to other lawmaker offices to reach consensus and build support, but he acknowledged that Republican backing — which eluded &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/16/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/richard-blumenthal-trump-military-comments-00183936" target="_blank"&gt;his past efforts&lt;/a&gt; — will be hard to get. He said he was "hopeful" but "not super confident" he might get support GOP senators who have bucked Trump before, such as Sens. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51218" data-person-id="51218"&gt;Lisa Murkowski&lt;/a&gt; (R-Alaska) and Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51168" data-person-id="51168"&gt;Susan Collins&lt;/a&gt; (R-Maine).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>12</id>
            <title>House Speaker says July 4 still the target for passing 'big beautiful bill'</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/johnson-trumps-megabill-is-still-on-track-00394985</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T15:54:14</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Speaker Mike Johnson still believes July 4 is a realistic target for passing President Donald Trump’s “big beautiful bill,” as Republicans in the Senate weigh changes to a package that cleared the House by just a single vote in May.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Johnson, while seated alongside Trump at a White House roundtable with business leaders on Monday, said he hopes the Senate uses a "light touch" in its modifications of the sweeping megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We certainly hope, I believe, we can still meet that,” Johnson said. “It's up to the Senate, the bill's in the Senate's hands now. But I spoke with Leader Thune as recently as last night, he's feeling very optimistic.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The president chimed in, telling reporters “I think it's gonna go pretty quickly.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson’s optimism comes even as the bill has faced major pushback from Elon Musk, the president’s one-time ally. Musk &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/03/elon-musk-trump-bill-00382653" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;panned the package last week&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, calling it “a disgusting abomination” and &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/04/elon-musk-republican-bill-trump-00386587" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;imploring Republicans&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to “kill the bill.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Work on the megabill &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/senate-republicans-to-huddle-wednesday-on-megabill-00394338" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;is continuing this week&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with Sens. John Boozman (R-Ark.) and Mike Crapo (R-Idaho) set to brief colleagues on some of the trickiest pieces of the package on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson cautioned the Senate against making too many changes to the House-passed version, lest it upset the delicate equilibrium in his caucus.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I've encouraged my dear friends and colleagues over there, don't modify it too much because we've got a very delicate balance that we reached,” he said. “And it took us a long time to get there. And we don't want to upset that balance too much. So they're putting their fingerprints on it.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>13</id>
            <title>Thune hopes to pass stablecoin bill this week</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/thune-stablecoin-bill-senate-crypto-00394734</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T15:40:09</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Senate Republicans are aiming to pass landmark cryptocurrency legislation that would create new rules for dollar-pegged digital tokens this week, Majority Leader &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/51242" data-person-id="51242"&gt;John Thune&lt;/a&gt; said Monday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We're trying to figure out if there's still a path forward on amendments, but the goal is to have it across the floor” this week, Thune said in a brief interview.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Thune filed cloture on the bill on Monday, teeing it up for another procedural vote as soon as Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;GOP leaders have been seeking to strike a deal on amendments that would allow them to proceed more quickly to a vote on final passage. But they have been unable to come to an agreement thus far, in large part due to a push by Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/259544" data-person-id="259544"&gt;Roger Marshall&lt;/a&gt; (R-Kan.) to force a vote on controversial legislation that aims to crack down on credit card swipe fees.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>14</id>
            <title>Thune and Johnson meet with Trump as megabill fights linger</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/thune-johnson-meets-with-trump-00394647</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T14:54:50</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Top Republican congressional leaders met separately with President Donald Trump at the White House on Monday as they try to finalize the "big, beautiful bill" before a self-imposed July 4 deadline.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Majority Leader John Thune met in private with Trump, according to a person granted anonymity to describe the undisclosed event, as Senate Republicans strain to settle several tricky provisions involving Medicaid, the state-and-local-tax deduction, key Trump tax priorities and more.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaker Mike Johnson, Ways and Means Chair Jason Smith (R-Mo.) and other GOP lawmakers later attended a White House event with Trump touting key tax provisions of the House-passed tax bill. They include a tax exemption for tips — something Senate Republicans are considering scaling down in order to fit in other business tax extensions and other Senate-side priorities.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Thune met with Senate Finance Chair Mike Crapo after returning to the Capitol. The tight-lipped Idaho Republican declined to discuss when he might have his piece of the bill ready but acknowledged that a key priority for many Senate Republicans — making certain business tax incentives permanent — is a "work in progress."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Thune could head back to the White House for more meetings this week. He's also in close contact with Johnson, who said at the White House event Monday that he talked with Thune on Sunday night and his message to Senate remains "don't modify it too much."&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>15</id>
            <title>Senior House Republican opposes White House proposal to cut public media funding</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/gop-opposition-to-public-media-funding-cuts-00394568</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T14:02:56</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;A top House Republican appropriator opposes the Trump administration’s plans to claw back funding for public media — a potential problem for GOP leaders who need near-unity within their party to pass the White House’s request that Congress revoke billions of dollars it has already approved.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Mark Amodei of Nevada, who leads the subcommittee with jurisdiction over the Department of Homeland Security, on Monday joined with Rep. Dan Goldman (D-N.Y.) to urge the administration to reconsider its proposal to cut $1.1 billion from the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, which funds PBS and NPR.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s a portion of the larger recissions package the administration sent to Capitol Hill last week to cut $9.4 billion previously greenlit by Congress, mainly for foreign aid.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Public media has demonstrated a willingness to listen to the American public and adapt,” said the two lawmakers, who are co-chairs of the Bipartisan Public Broadcasting Caucus, in a statement. “While we reaffirm that public media must be objective and legitimate concerns about content should be addressed, funding decisions should be objective as well.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Amodei and Goldman also noted that public media supports local jobs and the spread of information to rural constituents, and that cutting its funding does not significantly save money.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Public broadcasting represents less than 0.01% of the federal budget, yet its impact reaches every congressional district,” lawmakers said. “Cutting this funding will not meaningfully reduce the deficit, but it will dismantle a trusted source of information for millions of Americans.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump and many of his Republican allies have said NPR and PBS air programming biased against conservatives and shouldn’t receive government support. But Amodei joins a growing number of GOP lawmakers who want to tread carefully. Other Republicans are expressing concerns about cuts to global AIDS prevention efforts, too.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;House Majority Leader Steve Scalise last Friday introduced the rescissions package as a formal piece of legislation, with a floor vote expected later this week. It is unclear whether Amodei would vote against the package on the floor as it is, but leaders can only afford to lose three Republican votes and still pass the measure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We don’t share how he is planning to vote before a vote but he is looking at all of the information,” said Carrie Kwarcinski, a spokesperson for Amodei, in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>16</id>
            <title>Senate Republicans to huddle Wednesday on megabill</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/senate-republicans-to-huddle-wednesday-on-megabill-00394338</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T11:18:51</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Senate Republicans will huddle on Wednesday as they try to iron out some of the trickiest parts of their “big, beautiful bill.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;GOP senators are expected to be briefed by committee chairs who have yet to release their pieces of their &lt;a href="https://legislation.politicopro.com/bill/US_119_HR_1" target="_blank"&gt;party-line pack of tax cuts and extensions, border security investments, energy policy and more&lt;/a&gt;. Republicans held a similar meeting last week with panel leaders to discuss the less contentious parts of the bill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Finance Chair Mike Crapo is tentatively scheduled to be among the Republicans to update colleagues at Wednesday’s confab, according to five Republican senators and staff granted anonymity to share details of private deliberations. Senate Agriculture Committee Chair John Boozman is also likely to brief the conference.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The two Republican lawmakers are tasked with crafting some of the trickiest parts of the package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Crapo has the drafting pen both on his party's tax priorities, as well as changes to Medicaid and potentially Medicare. Senate Finance had been expected to release text this Friday, but Republicans are preparing for that to slip until early next week as they navigate the state-and-local-tax deduction cap and other sticking points.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Boozman, meanwhile, is facing pushback to a House proposal that would require states to cover part of the cost of federal food assistance benefits known as SNAP. At the same time the panel is struggling to hit the $150 billion in net savings Senate Republican leaders are pushing for the agriculture portion of the megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Senate Republican leaders had been the Agriculture Committee to expected to release text Wednesday, but that timeline is also looking tenuous as more governors over this past weekend raised private issues with the cost-share plans. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>17</id>
            <title>The Medicare tweak Republicans are eyeing for their megabill is actually bipartisan</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/medicare-tweak-megabill-no-upcode-act-00394281</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T10:16:47</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;A Medicare proposal some Republicans &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/medicare-is-a-target-as-senate-gop-faces-megabill-math-issues-00389537" target="_blank"&gt;want to include in their sweeping megabill&lt;/a&gt; has the backing of a key Democratic senator — though he doesn’t want it included in the party-line package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Jeff Merkley of Oregon said in a statement that he stands behind the No UPCODE Act, a bill co-sponsored with Louisiana Republican Bill Cassidy that tackles tools Medicare Advantage plans use to get higher payments from the federal government — calling it “common sense” that health insurers “shouldn’t be allowed to overcharge taxpayers for the care they deliver.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;However, he said in the statement to POLITICO, the legislation should instead be considered “through regular order, not in the context of a partisan bill that will end up leaving 16 million people without health care.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, Merkley’s statement standing up for the policy Republicans are now eyeing for their domestic policy agenda could give the GOP cover as they look to find more savings to offset costly tax cuts and other provisions. Including No UPCODE could generate more than $100 billion in savings and help Senate Republicans soften some politically tricky provisions in the House-passed megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House debated adding the bill to their version of the package but eventually relented after Republicans in battleground districts repeatedly warned it was too politically toxic. Now GOP senators say President Donald Trump — who had repeatedly pledged to keep Medicare intact — has privately blessed changes to the program so long as they are limited to addressing “waste, fraud and abuse.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even so, the discussion continues to cause heartburn in the GOP, with &lt;a href="https://x.com/jordainc/status/1930674978959004123" target="_blank"&gt;Sen. Josh Hawley of Missouri expressing outright opposition&lt;/a&gt; and a group of House moderates feeling blindsided by the Senate discussions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Key centrist Rep. Brian Fitzpatrick (R-Pa.) said he’d need to talk to Senate leadership about the scope of the proposal. “We specifically kept that out,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaker Mike Johnson demurred Friday when asked by POLITICO if he would advise Senate Republicans to avoid touching Medicare, saying they “haven’t addressed that yet.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s not yet clear to what extent Democrats will seek to weaponize any GOP attempts to target Medicare in their “big, beautiful bill” — and it could be tricky if the underlying policy Republicans embrace is bipartisan. So far the opposition messaging has focused largely on potential cuts to Medicaid, the joint federal-state health program for needy Americans.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Already, though, the possibility of adding the Cassidy-Merkley legislation to the megabill has generated fierce pushback from the insurance industry.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The president and CEO of the trade group representing most major U.S. health insurers said Monday that the group opposes No UPCODE and making any Medicare changes in the megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The President and Congressional leaders made a clear promise to seniors that there would be no cuts to Medicare as part of the budget reconciliation legislation," said Mike Tuffin of America's Health Insurance Plans. "Last-minute attempts to cut Medicare Advantage to fund other priorities would directly undermine that promise and lead to higher costs and reductions in benefits for more than 34 million seniors.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;And Mary Beth Donahue, president and CEO of advocacy group Better Medicare Alliance, which counts insurers among its members, said in a statement Friday that the legislation amounts to a cut to benefits and would “break a promise to millions of seniors who rely on it.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Cassidy said in a statement the legislation would help cut down on fraud and waste in Medicare Advantage, which lets older Americans get a private plan with additional benefits.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“To say the No UPCODE Act has bipartisan support is an understatement,” he said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jordain Carney contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>18</id>
            <title>Capitol agenda: Mike Crapo’s megabill Mission: Impossible</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/09/congress/what-were-watching-00394137</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T07:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;It’s shaping up to be an enormously consequential week for President Donald Trump’s legislative agenda, and there’s one lawmaker at the center of it all: Senate Finance Chair Mike Crapo.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Idaho Republican has a mammoth to-do list this week, which includes resolving make-or-break fights over tax policy, Medicaid cuts and clean energy credits. (POLITICO Pro readers got our &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/09/the-stealth-senate-dealmaker-who-could-deliver-trumps-tax-cuts-00393250" target="_blank"&gt;deeper dive&lt;/a&gt; first Sunday.)&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The soft-spoken Crapo has been stealthily working to coordinate changes to the “big, beautiful” bill. It's looking like he won't release his committee's piece of the package until next week, with several outstanding policy issues unresolved. Senate Finance is expected to begin going through bill text with members and staff beginning Monday, and Crapo is expected to brief the broader Senate Republican conference mid-week.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"We're working as aggressively as we can to move as fast as we can,” Crapo says.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Crapo’s leaning on a cadre of trusted advisers. Finance staff director Gregg Richard, chief tax counsel Courtney Connell and deputy chief tax counsel Randy Herndon are among his critical staff on the bill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Crapo is known for his spare words but also for his history of landing deals. One of his biggest wins was the 2018 law that eased the Dodd-Frank banking law — an effort that required bringing along Democrats to help serve up a Trump administration victory.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He also flexed as a deal killer last year, blocking a tax revamp negotiated by House Ways and Means Chair Jason Smith (R-Mo.) and then-Senate Finance Chair Ron Wyden (D-Ore.). &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Last year’s clash soured the relationship between Crapo and Smith, yet the two have found a way to work together to deliver Trump’s latest round of tax cuts.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We’ve been communicating very closely so we each know what the other is thinking,” Crapo says.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Now Crapo faces his biggest test yet as he tries to resolve Senate clashes over razor's-edge deals that Smith and other top House Republicans struck to pass their version of the bill. Some of those conflicts are within Senate Finance itself, with Sen. Thom Tillis (R-N.C.) pushing for changes to “no tax on tips” and Sen. James Lankford (R-Okla.) wanting to scale back planned endowment taxes on private universities.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Crapo’s personal priority? He is the leading advocate for using a legislative accounting method known as current policy baseline that would treat the extension of Trump’s 2017 tax cuts as costing nothing. This is a big flash point between him and fiscal hard-liners.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;If he succeeds in the Senate, Crapo’s compromise will have to survive the House. Some top House Republicans are urging him to go easy on them.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Mike Crapo is a brilliant senator and he's instrumental on the tax stuff and everything else. You got to respect his opinion,” Majority Whip Tom Emmer told POLITICO. “But at the end of the day, I hope they leave it right where it's at.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What else we’re watching:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— More megabill text this week: &lt;/b&gt;The Senate HELP and Energy committees are expected to release their text on Tuesday; Agriculture on Wednesday; and Homeland Security and Judiciary on Thursday, according to our latest intel. Agriculture text though may slide to later this week or possibly into next week as several governors are now raising concerns about plans for federal food aid.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— How lawmakers respond to immigration clashes: &lt;/b&gt;Congressional Hispanic Caucus members held an emergency meeting late Sunday after Trump mobilized the National Guard to respond to confrontations between law enforcement and protesters in Southern California over federal immigration policy. &lt;a href="https://x.com/LindseyGrahamSC/status/1931532246931939567" target="_blank"&gt;Sen. Lindsey Graham&lt;/a&gt; is among the GOP lawmakers using the clashes to call for passing the megabill. Look for the issue to come up at Monday’s House Appropriations subcommittee on DHS funding, which includes immigration enforcement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— Rescissions vote: &lt;/b&gt;House GOP leaders are planning to vote Thursday on a rescissions bill that would claw back $9.4 billion in funds Congress has approved for foreign aid and public broadcasting. But there’s a new problem for Speaker Mike Johnson – at least 10 moderate Republicans have privately said they currently oppose the legislation, according to four people with direct knowledge. The bill is scheduled to go to Rules on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Meredith Lee Hill, Katherine Tully-McManus and Nicholas Wu contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>19</id>
            <title>Florida’s GOP-controlled Legislature is about to wrap up work on the state’s budget with a series of significant steps designed to shore up reserves and curtail spending.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/09/florida-budget-republicans-finances-preparing-00392320</link>
            <description>Lawmakers in Tallahassee got to this point following a protracted and bumpy session, during which legislative leaders clashed over spending levels and tax cuts.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-09T05:55:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>6</id>
                <name>Gary</name>
                <surname>Fineout</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\afd2c18b-04fd-4ab7-9114-d048121c9e1a.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;TALLAHASSEE, Florida — In this hurricane-prone state, Republican legislators say they are preparing to weather a political and financial storm.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In other states led by Democrats, the moves by lawmakers could be labeled “Trump proofing.” But no matter the framing, Florida’s GOP-controlled Legislature is about to wrap up work on the state’s budget with a series of significant steps designed to shore up reserves and curtail spending.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The rationale given by Republican leaders includes everything from making the state’s budget resistant to a possible recession (without mentioning the economic impact of tariffs imposed by President Donald Trump) to acknowledging “uncertainty” associated with Congress and potential cuts to Medicaid, food aid and federal agencies responsible for helping with emergency efforts.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Should we have the expectation that if the federal government is spending less to get their budget and debt under control that we should be held harmless? I don’t think it works that way,” said Senate President Ben Albritton (R-Wauchula.) “The question is: ‘Do I believe this budget prepares Florida for what could be coming out of the ‘DOGE’ cuts or just the changes that come out of Washington D.C.?’ And I would say yes.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers in Tallahassee got to this point following &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/05/02/florida-legislature-session-end-no-budget-desantis-00324510" target="_blank"&gt;a protracted and bumpy session, during which legislative leaders clashed&lt;/a&gt; over spending levels and tax cuts. State House Speaker Daniel Perez (R-Miami) initially wanted to permanently lower Florida's sales tax rate, but he encountered headwinds from Senate Republicans as well as Gov. Ron DeSantis. DeSantis contended the sales tax rate cut would benefit tourists and would undercut his push to cut local property taxes.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;After being unable to come to a deal during their normal 60-day session, legislative leaders reached an accord late last week. &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/05/30/with-time-running-out-florida-legislators-forge-budget-deal-00378683" target="_blank"&gt;The final deal calls for $2.25 billion in “revenue reductions,”&lt;/a&gt; but part of that total includes steering extra money into state reserves while also dedicating money to paying down existing debt. The Legislature also intends to pass a proposed constitutional amendment that would ask voters to permanently increase the size of reserves.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Perez said his push was less about tax cuts and more about paring back spending he asserts had gotten out of control during DeSantis’ time as governor.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But he also argued it would give Florida extra money that could be tapped into if another recession happens. During the Great Recession of the late 2000s, Florida Republican legislators resorted to large budget cuts, but they also drew down reserves and voted to raise taxes and fees to make up the difference&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“None of us know what the future holds," said Perez. "When we had a recession, the state of Florida was not prepared for that recession. We began to scramble. ... We did not have the money that was necessary to protect Floridians. After this bill passes we will be in a better place.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Florida currently has billions in reserves, including a mandated “Budget Stabilization Fund.” They were able to reach that point because the state’s economy grew in the aftermath of the Covid epidemic, while Florida was also flush with billions that came from Congress as part of massive aid packages.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers are still tinkering with the current budget, but they are expected to land on a final total this month that puts overall state spending below the amount spent during the current fiscal year that ends on June 30.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Legislature is also taking steps to claw back billions in unspent money. On Thursday, lawmakers sent DeSantis a bill that would free up $2.1 billion that Florida had set aside three years ago to assist private insurance companies struggling with backup financing due to the state’s property insurance crisis. The money would have eventually reverted back to the state’s main budget account, but legislators decided to speed that up.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As the session has gone on, top Republicans have initially side stepped questions about how much federal grant money state universities lost due to cuts pushed by Elon Musk and the Department of Government Efficiency efforts. Likewise, there has been little debate or discussion about potential impacts to other programs that are heavily reliant on federal aid such as Medicaid.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Florida is also still waiting on money it previously requested from the Federal Emergency Management Agency in response to a flurry of hurricanes that have ripped through the state in recent years.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“There may not be a FEMA next year, none of us know that,” state Senate budget chief Ed Hooper (R-Palm Harbor) said while defending the legislative proposal to set aside extra money for the reserves.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Under the current plan legislators will set aside $1.5 billion over the next two years that will eventually roll into the “Budget Stabilization Fund” if voters ago along with the idea of increasing the size of that reserve.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Some Democrats — who contend the state already doesn’t spend enough on teachers, health care and other programs — raised questions this week about the efforts to put money away in a “lock box,” questioning how easily the Legislature could tap into the fund. The proposal going before voters says the state could withdraw money fund for a “critical state need,” even though that term isn’t defined.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s important to have flexibility because you never know what will come your way,” said state Rep. Christine Hunschofsky (D-Parkland).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Republican legislators backing the idea said they wanted to make sure the money was only used to deal with a financial crisis or emergency for the state.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We are doing this so we are truly prepared for a break-the-glass situation,” said Rep. Lawrence McClure (R-Dover), the House budget chief.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>20</id>
            <title>A series of public and private surveys show Texas Sen. John Cornyn (above) significantly trailing state Attorney General Ken Paxton in a primary matchup.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/07/john-cornyn-ken-paxton-poll-trump-movement-00393045</link>
            <description>An early May poll commissioned by the American Opportunity Alliance has the Texas incumbent down 17 points.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-07T09:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>7</id>
                <name>Ben</name>
                <surname>Jacobs</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\2553ade6-e215-47cb-bebf-78897d8de496.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;MAGA loyalists have put Sen. John Cornyn's reelection campaign in a &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2025/05/14/cornyn-paxton-texas-gop-primary-infighting-00346390" target="_blank"&gt;Texas-size hole&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;An early May poll commissioned by the &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2014/02/paul-singer-republican-gop-fundraising-campaigns-donors-103600" target="_blank"&gt;American Opportunity Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, a major conservative funding group linked to megadonor Paul Singer, shows the Texas Republican down 17 points in a head-to-head primary matchup with state attorney general Ken Paxton. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Below the top-line of Paxton's 52-percent-to-35-percent advantage, the &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/f/?id=00000197-470e-d063-a7b7-5f5e9b280000" target="_blank"&gt;poll found a clear divide&lt;/a&gt; between those voters who were defined as “Trump Movement” voters and those who were “Traditional Republicans.” In the former category, which made up of 58 percent of the electorate, Paxton had a 45-point lead. Among the latter, who made up only 35 percent of voters, Cornyn had a 27-point lead.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The findings reflect a increasingly prominent divide among Republican primary voters in Texas where an insurgent hard-right faction has been steadily gaining ground in recent years while ousting more traditional GOP elected officials. Paxton, who has faced federal investigation and impeachment, has long been a darling of right-wingers in Texas, while Cornyn — first elected to the Senate in 2002 — is considered a pillar of the establishment GOP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In a speculative three-way race with GOP Rep. Wesley Hunt, who is &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/wesley-hunt-texas-senate-cornyn-paxton-f5c0eb0dfffecdb2fdc96f838161661d" target="_blank"&gt;exploring a bid&lt;/a&gt;, the margin barely narrowed with the Cornyn trailing Paxton, 43 percent to 27 percent, with Hunt receiving 14 percent.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There was some good news for the incumbent in the poll. Despite trailing Paxton significantly, he is still viewed favorably by the Republican primary electorate in the Lone Star State — just not as favorably as the state attorney general.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The poll, conducted from April 29 through May 1 among 800 Republican primary voters, is among a series of public and private surveys all showing Cornyn significantly trailing Paxton. They have sparked increasing concern from national Republican operatives about a potentially ugly and costly primary, as well as the possible elevation of a scandal-plagued candidate who might be at risk in a general election. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The American Opportunity Alliance's interest in the race is notable; it's &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/politico-influence/2025/01/07/heller-heads-to-k-street-00196986" target="_blank"&gt;one of the key donor consortiums&lt;/a&gt; in Republican politics and its members including Singer and Chuck Schwab are some of the biggest funders on the right.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>21</id>
            <title>Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-Ga.), who helms the House DOGE subcommittee, blasted Musk’s "unwarranted" attacks on Trump.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/06/trump-musk-gop-congress-loyalty-00392731</link>
            <description>“Do not doubt, do not second-guess and don’t ever challenge the president of the United States," Speaker Mike Johnson said.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T15:20:36</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>8</id>
                <name>Meredith</name>
                <surname>Lee</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\f5aeb421-57c1-4308-bb58-d36dbc303208.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Amid the &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/06/elon-musk-gop-donald-trump-midterms-00391246" target="_blank"&gt;messy ongoing divorce&lt;/a&gt; between the president and the world’s richest man, this much is already clear: Donald Trump has sole custody of the House GOP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Republican lawmakers are making clear that, if forced to choose, it’s Trump — not Elon Musk — they’re sticking by as leaders race to contain the fallout for their “one big, beautiful bill.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene of Georgia, who helms a House panel inspired by Musk’s Department of Government Efficiency initiative, blasted Musk’s public attacks on Trump as “unwarranted” and criticized his “lashing out on the internet.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“America voted for Donald Trump on Nov. 4, 2024 — every single vote mattered just as much as the other,” Greene said in a brief interview. “And whether it was $1 that was donated or hundreds of millions of dollars, the way I see it, everybody's the same.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Like many Americans, GOP members watched Thursday's online exchange with a sense of car-crash-like fascination. Many shared that they hoped Musk and Trump &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/06/elon-musk-donald-trump-fight-fallout-00391732" target="_blank"&gt;could somehow patch things up&lt;/a&gt;. But many — including some of the former DOGE chief’s biggest backers on Capitol Hill — were wholly unsurprised to see the billionaire suddenly cut down to size after months of chatter about who was really calling the shots at the White House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s President Trump, not President Musk,” said one lawmaker granted anonymity to speak frankly about prevailing opinions inside the House GOP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Speaker Mike Johnson made no secret of where he stands on the public breakup.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He told reporters Friday that he hoped the two men “reconcile” and that it would be “good for the party and the country if all this worked out.” But in the nearly same breath, Johnson quickly reaffirmed his allegiance to the president and issued a warning to Musk.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Do not doubt, do not second-guess and don’t ever challenge the president of the United States, Donald Trump,” Johnson said. “He is the leader of the party. He is the most consequential political figure of this generation and probably the modern era. And he’s doing an excellent job for the people.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Other House Republicans concurred with the speaker’s assessment Friday, even as they faced the looming threat of Musk targeting them in the upcoming midterms or at least pulling back on his political giving after pouring more than $250 million into the 2024 election on behalf of Trump and the GOP ticket.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s unfortunate,” said Rep. Tim Moore (R-N.C.) of the breakup. “But Donald Trump was elected by a majority of the American people.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Warren Davidson of Ohio, who was one of only two Republicans to oppose Trump’s megabill in the House last month, also made clear he stood with the president over Musk.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“He does not have a flight mode — he's fight, fight, fight … and he's been pretty measured,” Davidson said of Trump. “I think Elon Musk looked a little out of control. And hopefully he gets back and grounded.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;GOP leaders who have spent weeks cajoling their members to vote for the sprawling domestic-policy bill hardly hid their feelings as Musk continued to bash the legislation online, even calling on Americans to call their representatives in an effort to tank it.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Frankly, it's united Republicans even more to go and defend the great things that are in this bill — and once it's passed and signed into law by August, September, you're going to see this economy turning around like nothing we've ever seen,” Majority Leader Steve Scalise said in a brief interview Friday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'll be waiting for all those people who said the opposite to admit that they were wrong,” Scalise added. “But I'm not expecting that to happen.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A few Republicans are still trying to walk a fine line by embracing both Trump and Musk — especially some fiscal hawks who believe Musk is right about the megabill adding trillions to the national debt.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I think Elon has some valid points about the bill, concerns that myself and a handful of others were working to address up until the passage of it,” Rep. Michael Cloud (R-Texas) said in an interview. “I think that'll make the bill stronger. I think it'll help our standing with the American people.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Both Trump and Musk “have paid a tremendous price personally for this country,” Cloud added. “And them working together is certainly far better for the country.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Notably, House Judiciary Chair Jim Jordan, a key Musk ally on the Hill, declined to engage Thursday when asked about the burgeoning feud. Instead, the Ohio Republican responded by praising the megabill Musk had moved to tank.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats, for their part, watched the unfolding and public breakup with surprise and a heavy dose of schadenfreude.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“There are no good guys in a fight like this,” Rep. Jared Huffman (D-Calif.). “You just eat some popcorn and watch the show.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>22</id>
            <title>13 House Republicans urge Senate to save green credits</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/house-republicans-push-on-green-credits-00392290</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T13:08:45</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Thirteen House Republicans are urging Senate leaders to “substantially and strategically” improve clean energy tax credit provisions in the House-passed megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Led by Rep. Jen Kiggans (R-Va.), the lawmakers said they remain “deeply concerned by several provisions” that would aggressively phase down incentives from the Democrats' 2022 climate law and add strict new supply chain requirements. Such steps could jeopardize billions of dollars in investments and thousands of jobs, companies and trade groups have said.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/eenews/f/eenews/?id=00000197-4634-dfde-abd7-76bf961c0000" target="_blank"&gt;letter Friday&lt;/a&gt; from Kiggans and Reps. Brian Fitzpatrick of Pennsylvania, Juan Ciscomani of Arizona and Andrew Garbarino of New York, among others, comes as Senate negotiators work on their version of the GOP's tax cut, energy and border spending budget package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We believe the Senate now has a critical opportunity to restore common sense and deliver a truly pro-energy growth final bill that protects taxpayers while also unleashing the potential of U.S. energy producers, manufacturers, and workers," the House lawmakers wrote in the letter addressed to Senate Majority Leader John Thune and Senate Finance Chair Mike Crapo.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Most lawmakers on the letter supported the House megabill despite the tax credit dispute. Garbarino slept through the early morning vote but said he would have supported the bill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The new letter calls for changing a provision that would cut off tax breaks for projects that haven’t started construction within 60 days of the megabill's enactment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Authors also want to change “highly restrictive and onerous” requirements for foreign entities of concern and revive the practice known as “transferability,” which allows project sponsors to transfer credits to a third party.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Even though the House-passed bill rolled back incentives for renewable energy and hydrogen, it spared credits for nuclear and biofuels.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Since January, over $14 billion in energy projects have been canceled or delayed, with $4.5 billion scrapped in April alone,” the House Republicans wrote. “Without a clear signal from Congress encouraging continued investments and offering business certainty as these provisions are phased out, project cancellations will continue to snowball.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House GOP effort will complement work already underway by Senate Republicans like Alaska's Lisa Murkowski and North Carolina's Thom Tillis to ease restrictions on the tax credits contained in the House bill.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>23</id>
            <title>Rep. Elise Stefanik questions witnesses during a House Education and Workforce Committee hearing on Capitol Hill on May 7.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/06/stefanik-house-intel-committee-00392168</link>
            <description>The GOP star returned to the committee after being dropped as President Donald Trump’s ambassador to the United Nations.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T12:59:30</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>10</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Sakellariadis</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\e34127d7-5801-4798-8ee2-f0440ab8b0bc.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Elise Stefanik is finally back on the House Intelligence Committee.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;On Friday morning, Speaker Mike Johnson added the New York Republican back to the influential spy panel, after months haggling over how to return the GOP star to her coveted committee post.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Stefanik was added to the committee under unanimous consent, along with Democratic Rep. Steve Cohen (D-Tenn.).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The congressmember was originally set to maintain her seat on the Intelligence Committee this January, but gave up the assignment when she was tapped to be U.S. ambassador to the United Nations. President Donald Trump pulled his selection back in March due to the GOP’s narrow majority in the House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;After her ambassador bid flamed out, Johnson said in April he intended to get Stefanik back on the committee. But fulfilling that promise put him in a bind: He could either strip a current Intelligence Committee Republican of a spot, or work with the minority to circumvent committee rules and add another Democrat.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson opted for the latter, pairing Stefanik with Cohen and expanding the panel past a limit under committee rules of 25 members.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for Johnson declined to comment on any potential deal with House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries (D-N.Y.). A spokesperson for Jeffries didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Cohen has been in Congress since 2007 but has never served on the Intelligence Committee.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Stefanik’s allies hold Johnson responsible for her losing out on the ambassador post, which could have given the Republican rising star a prominent voice in Trump’s foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson and Stefanik have been warring behind the scenes for several weeks as they have sought to restore her previous positions in Congress.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Tensions &lt;a href="https://x.com/EliseStefanik/status/1917229077645218163" target="_blank"&gt;spilled into public view&lt;/a&gt; in April when the congressmember publicly denied Johnson’s claims that the pair had spoken about potentially running for governor of New York.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The two &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/04/30/congress/mike-johnson-elise-stefanik-meeting-00319776" target="_blank"&gt;sat down together in April&lt;/a&gt; in a bid to resolve tensions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Stefanik has sat on the Intelligence Committee since 2017.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It was her role on the panel that catapulted her into the national spotlight in 2019 when the committee, then led by Democrats, spearheaded the first impeachment investigation into Trump.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Stefanik — once seen as a moderate Republican— emerged as a key defender of Trump in her prosecutorial questioning of witnesses and sharp rebukes of Democrats on the panel.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Meredith Lee Hill contributed to this report.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>24</id>
            <title>Two House Republicans issue megabill threats as Senate ponders changes</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/nick-lalota-chip-roy-megabill-red-lines-00392277</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T12:54:18</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Two House Republicans drew firm red lines Friday on changes to the House GOP megabill, threatening to vote “no” if the Senate made any changes whatsoever to key provisions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. Nick LaLota of New York warned GOP senators against lowering the House’s $40,000 cap on the state-and-local-tax deduction, while Rep. Chip Roy of Texas vowed to oppose any attempt to delay or otherwise water down the phaseout of clean-energy tax credits provided for in the House-passed megabill.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“If the Senate waters it down by a dollar, I’m a no,” LaLota &lt;a href="https://x.com/RepLaLota/status/1930998388763369766" target="_blank"&gt;posted on X&lt;/a&gt;, arguing that the SALT cap as it stands is “unfair” to his constituents.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Roy was equally strict about GOP senators’ hesitations on quickly phasing out clean-energy tax credits signed into law under former President Joe Biden — even calling out skeptical Sen. Thom Tillis (R-N.C.) by name in a floor speech Friday. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Tillis has been &lt;a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/senate-republicans-eye-saving-some-green-credits/" target="_blank"&gt;critical of the phaseouts&lt;/a&gt;, saying the House bill is “void of any understanding of just how these supply chains work.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“You backslide one inch on those IRA subsidies and I’m voting against this bill,” Roy said. “Because those god-forsaken subsidies are killing our energy, killing our grid, making us weaker, destroying our landscape, undermining our freedom. I’m not going to have it.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>25</id>
            <title>Senate Banking forges ahead with potentially problematic budget package</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/senate-banking-budget-package-megabill-big-beautiful-bill-00392118</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T12:16:13</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Senate Banking Chair &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/151800" data-person-id="151800"&gt;Tim Scott &lt;/a&gt;(R-S.C.) on Friday released his panel’s contribution to the GOP’s megabill, despite &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/06/banking-committee-megabill-plan-faces-concerns-over-senate-rules-00389584" target="_blank"&gt;concerns from his own members&lt;/a&gt; that several provisions won’t be allowed under Senate rules.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.banking.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/obbb_-_banking_textpdf.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;The committee’s text&lt;/a&gt; for its “one big beautiful bill” contributions includes zeroing out Consumer Financial Protection Bureau funding from the Federal Reserve, Fed pay scale changes and a rescission of funds from the &lt;a href="https://legislation.politicopro.com/bill/US_117_HR_5376" target="_blank"&gt;Inflation Reduction Act&lt;/a&gt;’s green housing initiatives. The bill would also sweep unused money from an SEC fund that allows the agency to spend money on technology modernization and eliminate the fund permanently. It would also dissolve the U.S.’s top audit regulator, the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board, and fold it into the SEC.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The panel is required to find $1 billion in cuts over the next 10 years under a budget resolution adopted by both chambers of Congress. House Financial Services’ version released last month was determined by the Congressional Budget Office &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/05/cbo-estimates-5-2-billion-in-savings-from-house-financial-services-megabill-contribution-00334518" target="_blank"&gt;to decrease deficits by $5.2 billion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Senate’s version goes further &lt;a href="https://legislation.politicopro.com/bill/US_119_HR_1" target="_blank"&gt;than the House&lt;/a&gt; with steeper cuts to CFPB funding.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The text remains almost identical to proposals the committee &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/06/senate-banking-republicans-prep-fed-pay-changes-zeroing-out-cfpb-funding-in-gop-megabill-00387491" target="_blank"&gt;laid out in a memo&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week. But after GOP committee members met Thursday to discuss the legislation, a number of lawmakers raised questions about whether it can comply with the strict rules governing the filibuster-skirting budget reconciliation process, which allows only measures that are aimed at changing spending or revenues.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I’d love to have [CFPB funding] be zeroed out, but I think we all know that that would be a policy issue as much as a budget issue,” Sen. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/221844" target="_blank"&gt;Mike Rounds&lt;/a&gt; (R-S.D.), a senior member of the Banking Committee, said Thursday. “While we’d like to see that happen, we understand the parliamentarian may have a disagreement on that.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jasper Goodman contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>26</id>
            <title>Mary Miller says she’s ‘deeply troubled’ by Sikh man leading House floor prayer in deleted xenophobic post</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/05/congress/mary-miller-sikh-prayer-00391748</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T11:23:50</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Rep. Mary Miller (R-Ill.) said in a since-deleted social media post on Friday it was “deeply troubling” that a Sikh man, whom she initially misidentified as Muslim, led a prayer on the floor of the House.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Miller &lt;a href="https://x.com/nicholaswu12/status/1931006317017149514" target="_blank"&gt;wrote on X that the man&lt;/a&gt;, Giani Surinder Singh, “should never have been allowed” to lead the prayer and called for Congress to uphold the “truth” that “America was founded as a Christian nation.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Miller’s original post incorrectly identified Singh as Muslim. She subsequently corrected the post before deleting it entirely.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Singh was invited to lead the prayer, a regular tradition ahead of House sessions being called to order, by Rep. Jeff Van Drew (R-N.J.).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Miller did not respond to a request for comment. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Following Singh’s prayer, Van Drew praised him for his work leading a Sikh congregation in New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Day after day, year after year, he leads not just with words, but with example, with peace, with humility, with service towards all,” Van Drew said on the House floor. “These are not just Sikh values. They are American values.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Harman Singh, executive director of the Sikh Coalition, a nonprofit focused on protecting civil rights for the Sikh community, called on Miller to apologize for her “hateful rhetoric” and urged her to meet with Sikhs in her district.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Congresswoman Miller should apologize for her remarks — to both the Sikh and Muslim communities, because no one should be targeted on the basis of their identity,” Singh said in a statement to POLITICO. “We encourage Congresswoman Miller to learn this lesson from her Sikh constituents, and would be happy to facilitate these conversations.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Haris Tarin, vice president of the Muslim Public Affairs Council, condemned Miller’s “Islamaphobia” and called on her to apologize while pushing back on Miller’s belief that the U.S. is a Christian nation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We were intentionally founded as a nation of all faiths,” Tarin told POLITICO. “Apparently she must have forgotten about the First Amendment in this country.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Some lawmakers immediately condemned Miller’s post. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It's deeply troubling that someone with such contempt for religious freedom is allowed to serve in this body,” Rep. Bonnie Watson Coleman (D-N.J.) &lt;a href="https://x.com/repbonnie/status/1931014439999857128" target="_blank"&gt;posted on X&lt;/a&gt;. “This should have never been allowed to happen.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It’s deeply troubling that such an ignorant and hateful extremist is serving in the United States Congress,” House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries &lt;a href="https://x.com/RepJeffries/status/1931048357650378798" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;said on X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “That would be you, Mary.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'm troubled by my colleague's remarks about this morning's Sikh prayer, which have since been deleted,” Rep. David Valadao (R-Calif.) &lt;a href="https://x.com/repdavidvaladao/status/1931027570067226627?s=46" target="_blank"&gt;wrote on X&lt;/a&gt;. “Throughout the country—and in the Central Valley— Sikh-Americans are valued and respected members of our communities, yet they continue to face harassment and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus — whose membership is comprised of solely Democratic lawmakers — accused Miller of “anti-Sikh and anti-Muslim bigotry” for conflating the two religions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Sikhs and Muslims practice two separate and distinct religions, and conflating the two based on how someone looks is not only ignorant but also racist,” the group &lt;a href="https://x.com/CAPAC/status/1931027448923042103" target="_blank"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>27</id>
            <title>House Speaker Mike Johnson (R-La.) stops to speak with reporters outside his office at the U.S. Capitol, on June 6, 2025.</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/06/elon-musk-donald-trump-fight-fallout-00391732</link>
            <description>Republicans are seeking to deescalate the situation after a blowup fight between the president and his top adviser.</description>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T10:22:34</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>12</id>
                <name>Giselle</name>
                <surname>Ruhiyyih</surname>
            </creator>
            <picturepath>assets\64e66427-43a9-45c5-b827-65737da9d0fe.jpg</picturepath>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Republicans are hoping for a détente between Donald Trump and Elon Musk after Thursday’s blowup, warning that the fight between the two men could distract from the president’s agenda and derail Congress’ “Big Beautiful Bill.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The battle between the president and the world’s richest man escalated from a simmer to a &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/trump-musk-fight-online-00390885" target="_blank"&gt;full-on scorched-earth showdown&lt;/a&gt; over the course of the day on Thursday — starting with light criticism in the morning that escalated to &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/elon-musk-federal-contracts-trump-00390319" target="_blank"&gt;Trump targeting Musk’s pocket book&lt;/a&gt; and Musk saying the president was an associate of a notorious convicted sex criminal and suggesting he &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/elon-musk-donald-trump-recession-impeachment-00390762" target="_blank"&gt;may need to be impeached&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I just hope it resolves quickly, for the sake of the country,” Speaker &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/242539" data-person-id="242539"&gt;Mike Johnson&lt;/a&gt; told CNBC’s “Squawk Box” on Friday morning.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;POLITICO reported Thursday night that White House aides were looking to broker a peace between the two men and were planning on scheduling a call between the two camps.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it’s OK,” Trump told &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/trump-white-house-aides-signal-a-possible-detente-with-musk-00391502?nname=playbook&amp;amp;nid=0000014f-1646-d88f-a1cf-5f46b7bd0000&amp;amp;nrid=00000153-e6bc-def3-a35f-fefd46980000" target="_blank"&gt;POLITICO in a brief telephone call&lt;/a&gt; Thursday when asked about the very public breakup. “It’s going very well, never done better.” Trump went on to tout his favorability ratings saying, “The numbers are through the roof, the highest polls I’ve ever had and I have to go.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A senior administration official and a person close to the White House — both granted anonymity to discuss the president’s thinking around the blowup — said the president had been convinced Thursday night that continuing to engage with Musk would be counterproductive and a distraction from a host of good news the White House should be focused on, from &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/trump-xi-call-trade-00388997" target="_blank"&gt;his talks with Xi Jinping&lt;/a&gt; to negotiating a deal with Iran and ushering his “big beautiful” reconciliation bill through Congress, which was the root cause of the blowup.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Trump has displayed some lingering frustration with his one-time benefactor. He &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/day-after-blistering-exchange-trump-calls-elon-musk/story?id=122567621" target="_blank"&gt;told ABC News&lt;/a&gt; that Musk has "lost his mind" — and he is "not particularly" interested in talking to Musk. He &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/politics/live-news/trump-elon-musk-news-06-06-25" target="_blank"&gt;also told CNN&lt;/a&gt; that “the poor guy’s got a problem.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, Republican legislators Friday are following Johnson’s lead, keeping with the theme of deescalation in the fallout of the public fight.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Both of them have paid a tremendous price personally for this country, and I think at the end of the day, they're both going to put the country first," said Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/300715" data-person-id="300715"&gt;Michael Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (R-Texas). "And them working together is certainly far more better for the country.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Department of Government Efficiency caucus Chair Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/240045" data-person-id="240045"&gt;Aaron Bean&lt;/a&gt; (R-Fla.) said Friday he was “shocked and dismayed” to see his “two friends fighting,” but remains an “optimist” that the former allies can work it out.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I believe there's a Diet Coke in their future, that they can settle it and cooler heads will prevail,” Bean said. “We need them together. We need to be united, and we're stronger together. So I'm very optimistic that there will be a happy ending very soon.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But even as they seek to not escalate the fight, party faithfuls are still making clear where their allegiances lie.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I don't tell my friend Elon how to — I don't argue with him about how to build rockets. And I wish he wouldn't argue with me about how to craft legislation and pass it,” Johnson told CNBC.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He later told reporters on Capitol Hill that “I hope they reconcile. I believe in redemption. … I think it’s good for the party and the country if all this worked out. But I tell you what: do not doubt, do not second guess and don’t ever challenge the president of the United States, Donald Trump.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Rep. &lt;a href="https://directory.politicopro.com/member/361717" data-person-id="361717"&gt;Troy Nehls&lt;/a&gt; (R-Texas) went a step further, saying he thinks “Elon is getting too personal” in his attacks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“It's getting out of control,” Nehls said Thursday. “They got to stop it. I think it's, you know, it's not healthy. And some of the most recent comments, I think, Elon, you've lost your mind.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Johnson — who was also targeted by Musk Thursday — largely on Friday kept his cool in responding to Musk, brushing off his claim that he landed Republicans their 2024 victory.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Elon was a big contributor in the last election,” the speaker acknowledged to CNBC, “but this was a whole team effort. I mean, President Trump is the most consequential political figure of his generation — of modern American history. He is the one responsible for that. But we all worked hard. We delivered the House majority."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The speaker said he was with the president in the Oval Office for part of the showdown on X, a meeting &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/05/congress/mike-johnson-white-house-00390710" target="_blank"&gt;reported earlier by POLITICO&lt;/a&gt;. Trump seemed “disappointed” by Musk’s attacks, the speaker said, reiterating that he is a “huge fan and supporter of President Trump” for good measure. He told POLITICO Friday he hasn’t spoken with Musk yet.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The White House has sought to project an air of calm despite Musk’s relentless attacks — but aides there remain wary of the Tesla CEO popping off again.The two people close to the president said several Trump allies — including at least one White House official — tried to reach Musk by phone when he was on his rampage on X, but Musk was not taking calls for a time.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The way Musk reacted to the president’s comments made White House officials feel like they were dealing with an “unhinged” situation, the senior administration official said Thursday — and that they had to just ignore what he was doing. Musk did not immediately respond to a request for comment sent via press or personal contact information for his companies.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Everybody is just like, ‘OK, this is manic and crazy,’” the official said, “and we're just gonna move along and pass the bill. And that's kind of the feeling of everyone right now.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mia McCarthy contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>28</id>
            <title>House passes bill to restrict SBA loans for noncitizens</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/house-passes-sba-bill-00391744</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T10:18:07</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;The House has passed legislation that would ward off noncitizens from receiving Small Business Administration loans, bringing agency-driven SBA policy shifts from earlier this year a step closer to codification into law.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The bill passed Friday 217-190, with eight Democrats joining all Republicans in voting for it. If passed by the Senate and signed by President Donald Trump, the legislation would require applicants for SBA loans to submit documentation proving their citizenship status. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“We cannot allow those kinds of folks that are in our country illegally to take money away from hardworking Americans who are applying for SBA taxpayer-backed loans,” Rep. Beth Van Duyne (R-Texas), a sponsor of the legislation, said on the House floor.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Democrats countered that Republicans have shared no evidence that SBA loans are being distributed among business owners who are noncitizens.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s be honest about what this bill really does: It uses small business policy as a vehicle for immigration politics,” said Rep. LaMonica McIver (D-N.J.). “That is not only misguided — it’s harmful.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration rolled out a rule in recent months to block noncitizen business owners from borrowing money from the SBA. It came about after an audit uncovered the agency had approved in June 2024 an SBA loan of $783,000 for the owner of a small business that was partially owned by someone without citizenship status.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The House passed another bill Thursday afternoon that would relocate local SBA offices from so-called sanctuary cities to jurisdictions that comply with federal immigration enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>29</id>
            <title>GOP Whip Emmer weighs in on megabill's fate — and Musk</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/emmer-on-megabill-00391609</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T08:47:58</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;House Majority Whip Tom Emmer isn’t concerned about the GOP megabill’s fate in the Senate, despite a raft of current policy disputes in need of speedy resolution. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;He's also not worried about Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'm not watching what Elon is posting. I've heard about it, but sorry, he's not on my phone," said the Minnesota Republican in an exclusive interview Thursday, as the freshly-departed DOGE chief raged against the massive tax and spending package Republicans want to send to President Donald Trump’s desk by July 4.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"What I'm thinking about is this: I get the bill that's ... the largest reduction in spending, and preventing the largest tax increase, in history," Emmer continued. "It seals the southern border. It pays for defense. I mean, it is every one of President Trump's priorities. And, you know, I think there was some suggestion earlier this week that it was like pork-filled whatever. It's not a spending bill."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Asked what must be motivating Musk to urge lawmakers to "kill the bill" at this time, Emmer chalked it up to high emotions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;"Look, all I care about is the bill that we passed and making sure that when the Senate sends back whatever they're going to send back that, we pass it ... That's all I care about. All this other stuff is just noise," he said. "Everybody loves a great car accident. They just don't want to be in it, right? So, okay, let them dust up. This is what we had in the house when we were going through the process. There's a lot of emotion involved. There's a lot of intense pressure."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Emmer was bullish about the megabill's prospects.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“The Senate will do their work. They're going to send the bill back to us,” Emmer said. “We are going to pass it and send it to the president's desk. The time for talking is over.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There's one area, however, that Emmer said he hopes the Senate won’t touch: the quadrupled state and local tax deduction cap carefully negotiated with blue-state Republicans in the House. Senate Finance Chair Mike Crapo recently said there’s little appetite among his members for keeping the increase fully intact. But Emmer said he believes the Senate understands the House’s more difficult math.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“John Thune was quoted somewhere as saying, you know, ‘We understand it's 51 over here and it’s 218 over there.’” Emmer said. “That should tell you everything you need to know.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Emmer also said he believes the Republican senators who have raised concerns on the House's Medicaid overhaul proposals — specifically Sens. Susan Collins of Maine, Lisa Murkowski of Alaska and Josh Hawley of Missouri— are “going to be pleasantly surprised when they go through” the House-passed package.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of their concerns that they thought they were going to have are just not there,” Emmer insisted, adding that “there might be” tweaks from across the chamber to the House's product, but no one has flagged any “major problems” in the bill. Emmer said the only area he thinks there might be unease is &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/06/05/medicare-is-a-target-as-senate-gop-faces-megabill-math-issues-00389537" target="_blank"&gt;about the provider tax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A key group of senators could also hold up the bill over the House's moves to repeal or scale back the clean-energy tax credits that were created by the Democrats' 2022 climate law. Disrupting the long-term availability of those credits could disrupt projects already underway in red districts and states. Emmer said House members are sensitive to this dynamic as well.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“That's one of the reasons why the sunsetting [of certain credits] is out at least three years, so that people can continue projects and repurpose them,” said Emmer. “That was the whole concept. Whatever the Senate does with it, that's their business.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Emmer weighed in, too, on Speaker Mike Johnson's suggestion that Republicans could pursue a second megabill through the filibuster-skirting, party-line budget reconciliation process — or even a third. The majority whip didn’t wave off the idea but emphasized that Congress should “get the first one done.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“All of it's possible,” Emmer said. “Is it probable? We’ll see.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
        <article>
            <id>30</id>
            <title>Capitol agenda: GOP leaders rush into Elon Musk damage control</title>
            <link>https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/06/congress/musk-trump-johnson-republican-megabill-00391554</link>
            <publisheddate>2025-06-06T07:00:00</publisheddate>
            <creator>
                <id>2</id>
                <name>John</name>
                <surname>Doe</surname>
                <email>jdoe@algebra.hr</email>
            </creator>
            <content>&lt;p&gt;Hill GOP leaders are in full-on damage control as they scramble to save their megabill — and themselves — from the blast radius of President Donald Trump and Elon Musk’s breakup.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But Musk doesn’t seem interested in sparing any part of the GOP trifecta from his wrath on his way out of Washington. The president’s new enemy &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/05/congress/elon-musk-attacks-johnson-thune-00390273" target="_blank"&gt;attacked both Speaker Mike Johnson and Senate Majority Leader John Thune&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday over the cost of the party’s sweeping domestic policy package. Thune brushed it aside.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson, however, is &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/elon-musk-mike-johnson-megabill-00390657" target="_blank"&gt;mounting a multi-front rebuttal&lt;/a&gt; as he aims to keep Musk from hurting the megabill’s prospects. He’s questioning the tech mogul’s motives for opposing the bill and challenging his claims about its impact on the deficit. Johnson already had to reassure hard-liners concerned about the bill’s spending in order to squeeze the bill through the House last month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I'm the same guy that's always been a deficit hawk, and now I'm the speaker of the House, and I'm working on a multi-step plan to reverse the fiscal insanity that has haunted our country,” Johnson told reporters Thursday. “We have to get the big, beautiful bill done.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Johnson’s leadership team quickly claimed Musk wouldn’t rattle their members. House Majority Leader Steve Scalise insisted it hadn’t moved any votes. And House Majority Whip Tom Emmer, &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/06/politico-pro-q-a-rep-tom-emmer-00391492" target="_blank"&gt;in an exclusive interview with POLITICO&lt;/a&gt;, said he’s not tracking Musk’s onslaught on X.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Sorry,” Emmer said, “he’s not on my phone.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Some fiscal hard-liners — who share in Musk’s concerns about the bill but allowed it to pass the House — avoided immediately picking sides in the feud. Freedom Caucus Chair Andy Harris (R-Md.), bombarded with questions about Musk on Thursday, said only that he’s “right on the deficit.” Sen. Mike Lee (R-Utah) &lt;a href="https://x.com/BasedMikeLee/status/1930735981323251878" target="_blank"&gt;posted on X&lt;/a&gt;: “But … I really like both of them.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;They may not have to choose. Signs of a détente emerged late Thursday, with Trump &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/06/05/trump-white-house-aides-signal-a-possible-detente-with-musk-00391502" target="_blank"&gt;brushing off the clash in a phone call&lt;/a&gt; with POLITICO and Musk &lt;a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1930798791806050496" target="_blank"&gt;seeming somewhat open to a reconciliation&lt;/a&gt; (just not &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; reconciliation bill). White House aides are working to broker peace.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Still, if the Trump-Musk divorce goes through, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2025/06/05/steve-bannon-trump-musk-rachael-bade-00391135" target="_blank"&gt;MAGA will likely side with the president&lt;/a&gt;. There were signs Thursday that Musk was alienating some of Trump’s biggest Hill boosters.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Elon is getting too personal. It's getting out of control,” Rep. Troy Nehls (R-Texas) told POLITICO. “Some of the most recent comments, I think: Elon, you've lost your mind.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;What else we’re watching:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— Rescissions deadline:&lt;/b&gt; Congress &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/06/05/congress/congress-has-until-july-18-to-act-on-trumps-request-to-claw-back-9-4b-00391029" target="_blank"&gt;must act by July 18 on Trump’s request to claw back $9.4 billion&lt;/a&gt; in funding or the White House will be required to spend the money, the Senate parliamentarian said. The House is expected to vote next week to approve the request, as submitted. But Senate Republicans are considering their options for making tweaks to the package. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;— AI update for the megabill: &lt;/b&gt;Senate Commerce Chair Ted Cruz (R-Texas) said Thursday his committee would &lt;a href="https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/2025/06/cruz-ai-moratorium-00390202" target="_blank"&gt;attempt to rewrite the 10-year moratorium&lt;/a&gt; on enforcement of state and local artificial intelligence laws that the House tucked into its version of the megabill. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rachael Bade, Dasha Burns and Meredith Lee Hill contributed to this report.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        </article>
    </articles>
</articlearchive>
